Sanjog Thapa

+1 (256) 694 - 8208 (M) | sanzog03@gmail.com (E) | LinkedIn | Github | www.sanjogthapa.com.np

SUMMARY

With a cumulative experience of 5+ years as a Software Engineer, I have contributed to the creation and enhancement of software products known for their outstanding availability, scalability, and reliability. I have consistently showcased my coding proficiency and familiarity with architectural patterns for large, high-scaled applications.

SKILLS

Language: JavaScript, Typescript, Python, C, MATLAB, Ruby

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, RESTful APIs, ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Django, WebSockets, JWT, GraphQL

Cloud Services Platform: AWS Lambda, AWS EC2, AWS S3, AWS API Gateway, AWS Cloudwatch

Database: PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, DynamoDB

Data Science Tools: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Xarray, Jupyter Notebooks, Cesium, CZML, 3DTiles

Build Tools: Webpack, Terraform, Docker

Other Tools: Git, Linux/Bash, RabbitMQ, JIRA, Confluence, Spreadsheets

WORK EXPERIENCE

NASA GHRC DAAC, ITSC UAH

Graduate Research Assistant

Huntsville, AL, USA

Aug 2022 - Present

- Released an open-source Python package for cloud-native interactive visualization playground for NASA GHRC, providing a more comprehensive and lucid view of atmospheric science data.
- Implemented a cloud-based data subsetting tool using RESTful API services in Python and dockerized serverless microservices in AWS, resulting in a 70% increased efficiency for subsetting on large Geospatial data.
- Led the development of a cloud-native 3D visualization/simulation tool in ReactJS including multiple data processing pipelines in Python and AWS Lambda to represent a variety of big data together and efficiently over the globe.

GURZU INC Boston, MA, USA

Software Engineer

Aug 2020 - Aug 2022

- Led a team of associate engineers using MERN stack, through a close collaboration with architects and stakeholders.
- Played a pivotal role in establishing standard practices for streamlining NodeJS product commencements.
- Worked closely with the product owners and stakeholders to understand and build custom add-on features needed for digital ads software using ReactJS, enhancing operational efficiency by 40% and increasing reliability.

JYAASA TECHNOLOGIES

Kathmandu, Nepal

Associate Software Engineer

Jan 2019 - Aug 2020

- Designed and developed RESTful APIs, and integrated them with distributed services using RabbitMQ for message passing, as a part of the implementation of a resilient desktop application for a cloud-native digital billboard solution.
- Implemented authentication backend and WebSockets for highly available real-time inventory management system.
- Participated in peer code reviews for applications ensuring compliance with the company coding standards and organized several knowledge-sharing activities across the company.

TECHNORIO INC

Kathmandu, Nepal

Software Engineer Intern

Sep 2018 - Dec 2018

- Implemented the provided mockup using HTML, jQuery, and responsive CSS code.
- Collaborated with teams to enhance the existing design and performance, ensuring the feasibility of UI/UX designs.

EDUCATION

University Of Alabama In Huntsville

Huntsville, AL

Masters in Computer and Information Science

Graduation Date: Dec 2023